Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.SubtitleDB.org today
Leaving is a form of dying.
One never arrives until
being at rest with You.
You Lord, in your sudden flight
from Egypt, across sown paths...
multiplied the bread and
healed the sick with the gospel...
...before returning to the Father
with Your ascent.
You took Abraham, father
of all believers, from his land.
You showed him
the path to reach you.
You, Lord, experienced migration.
And You brought it upon all men
who know what it is to live...
...and who seek safe passage
to the gates of Heaven.
I'm sorry.
I can never find the button.
Squeeze its balls.
I've already tried that.
There it is!
I told you!
Goddammit!
It's broken down, Lobo.
Bring the stick
that's behind the seat.
Lobo!
Go see if there's
a mechanic back there.
But quickly!
Any of you know about cars?
Come over here.
- Hey, Don Primi.
- Yeah?
This one.
- Are you a mechanic?
- Yes.
Take a look at this.
See if you can fix it.
Shit.
It just broke down?
It was jerking around.
Didn't you feel it?
Yes.
Take a look
and see what's wrong.
It's just that sometimes...
...if this shit heats up...
- Be careful...
- Careful, it's hot.
There you go.
- What the hell's wrong with it?
- Look at this.
- What is that?
- The brush is screwed.
So fix it! You're a mechanic!
That can't be fixed.
It has to be towed.
Who the fuck
is going to tow us?
I don't know.
- Excuse me.
- Whatever.
Yes, boss?
The truck broke down.
We're stranded near the badlands.
Hey...
Do you know
if we're gonna cross over here?
They're figuring it out
There's twelve. And two more
that we picked up in San Pedro.
I'll tell them. Okay then.
Don't worry about it.
Lobo, I've got bad news.
You're crossing through
the badlands.
What are you talking about?
We agreed to cross at Sote.
That was before.
Look at the truck.
This route is longer
and more dangerous.
I know, but we can't
just leave them here.
No, you're right
Look Don Primi,
I would never let you down.
I'll do it, but it'll be
more expensive.
Come on Lobo,
don't break my balls!
Okay. 100 pesos each,
but get moving.
200, Don Primi.
Fucking Lobo!
200.
But round up the cattle, quickly!
Let's go.
- Lobo...
- What?
We said we wouldn't do
the badlands.
What?
Are you afraid of getting lost?
No, but you know what happened
to the Sonoyta gang.
Those idiots were running drugs
and got killed by the cartel.
Don't whine.
You even got a bonus!
Listen.
The United States is that way.
Okay?
Come on! Get out of the truck!
Move. move!
Come on!
Can you throw me
my backpack, please?
Keep an eye on them.
They are worth a lot of money.
Good luck and be safe.
God bess you.
Come on, hurry up!
Let's go!
Hurry up!
Welcome to the United States,
scumbags.
From now on we have
to be very careful.
If you see or hear anything...
...even if it's a fucking rancher,
you've got to hide.
Is that clear?
Hey you, come help him!
Hold the fence so we can cross.
Let's go!
Hurry up!
Get down!
Come on.
Run! Run! To the bushes!
Come on! Come on!
Hurry up!
Run! Come on, assholes!
- It's your first time crossing?
- Yes. It's my first time.
Do you have family there?
Yes. Cousins...
Lobo...
Don't drink all your water,
we've still got a day and a half to go.
You've been warned.
What do you want?
Come over here!
Leave me alone!
Listen to me, you jerk!
I've only known you for three days.
My parents asked you to take care
of me, but you're not my husband.
Don't overreact!
It's not a big deal.
Hey, man... Hey!
You have a cigarette?
- What?
- You don't have a cigarette?
I don't smoke.
Me neither.
But this lady is asking you
to leave her alone.
That's none of your business.
I know, it's just that...
we're trying to rest...
...it's hot...
Cheer up and let's go!
Let's go!
Hurry!
- Hurry up!
- I'm walking as fast as I can!
Do you want help
with your bag?
No... I'm fine.
It's okay, we can take turns.
Let me help you for a few minutes.
No, thanks.
Lobo!
Wait for us!
Lobo! Wait, asshole!
Don't be a jerk!
Don't leave us!
Fucking asshole!
Hurry up!
Move it, assholes!
Can't you see they're leaving us?
Goddammit!
What's wrong?
I'm exhausted.
You don't have a choice, man.
I know it's hard.
Come on!
Let's go!
Breathe, just breathe.
Have you crossed before?
- What?
- Have you crossed before?
Yeah.
No one told me
it'd be this hard.
I just want to get there.
Okay.
Just take a deep breath
and walk. Come on.
They left us.
Lobo!
Sir...
Your friend's back there.
That's what happens
when you're slow.
Hurry up or you'll end up
like those assholes!
Down! Get down!
Hide! Everyone hide!
- What?
- The truck!
Oh shit!
Who's that?
- The Border Patrol?
- No.
No, it's not, right?
No.
Oh shit!
They're shooting at us!
Run!
Stay close!
Come on, come on!
Let's go.
What do we do, man?
I don't know.
Don't go!
Come on!
Go! Go!
Hey!
Wait!
Let's go! Come on!
Hurry, hurry!
Ramiro!
Come on! Don't turn around!
Dog!
Hurry! Hurry!
Now what?
What do we do?
Come on!
Jump!
Go!
I can't!
I'll catch you!
Good job!
You did it!
Man!
Hey, man!
Wait for us!
Wait!
What?
Which way?
I don't know!
I told Lobo not to come this way!
I don't even know this place!
So what do we do?
We have to stay together.
So don't leave us, okay?
Come on.
Will you hold me?
I got it.
Okay.
Let's go.
Move back!
Please... Help me.
Listen.
I'm sorry for the guy
you were with.
I barely knew him.
My parents hired him
to help me cross the border.
That asshole did
awful things to me.
But he didn't deserve
to die like that.
No one deserved
I didn't even want to come.
My parents forced me to.
They say our town
is very dangerous.
That I'd be safer here.
If only they knew
what things are like here.
I have a son
waiting for me in Oakland.
I had already applied...
...for my residence visa.
One day, a cop stopped me
because of a broken headlight.
One thing led to another...
...and I ended up
in a Detention Center.
Just before I got deported,
my son came to visit and...
...he gave me this teddy bear...
...to take care of me
when they sent me back to Mexico.
I told him that...
...that I would get it back to him.
My wife told me...
...not to tell that to my son...
...not to make empty promises.
She said I never keep
my promises.
That I would take this opportunity
to disappear.
No fucking way.
I don't want to disappear.
You know about cars, don't you?
Why?
The gringo is over there!
Where?
Over there.
Let's steal his truck.
But first we have
to get rid of the dog.
I'll take care of the dog.
I'll just need
your teddy bear.
Come on!
He's coming!
Wait!
Got it!
There it is!
Let's go!
What did I tell you?
I'll drive you straight to Chicago!
Fucking gringos, kiss my ass!
Hang on.
Hang on tight!
Wait. Hold on!
Enough! I can't do this anymore.
I can't... I don't feel good.
Let's stop here and rest a little.
Okay! Here you go.
It's okay. It's okay.
I'm gonna have
to leave you here.
You can't walk.
I have to leave you here.
If I stay, we'll both die.
If you leave, he will kill me.
He'll kill me too.
And I have a son.
Don't leave me here.
I don't want to die alone, please.
Forgive me. Keep the water.
Goddammit.
Over here!
Help!
Help me!
Somebody help me!
Fucking gringo,
don't you ever get tired?
You killed them all!
As if we were animals!
Son of a bitch.
You're a son of a bitch!
Let the desert kill you.
Come.
Come on, let's go.
Just one last push.
We're almost there.
The highway is right there.
One last push.
Carry on.
Come on, carry on.
Please rate this subtitle at %url%
Help other users to choose the best subtitles